3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Audition
How many people are supposed be here today?
（木下(きのした)）
今日 何人来るんだっけ？
38 in the morning and 67 in the afternoon.
（中田）
午前38 午後67人ですね
It's just... My ears start going numb after about a dozen...
俺ね 13人以上になると
耳がウニウニしちゃうんだよね
Don't say things like that, director!
（葛城(かつらぎ)）
監督がそんなこと言っちゃダメ！
Sorry.
あっ すんません…
It's gonna get a second season, right?
（稲浪(いななみ)）
これってきっと
２期もあるんでしょ？
For the past year, there have been rumors that you've got it in the bag, NabeP.
ナベＰ持ってるって
もっぱらのウワサだよ
去年あたりから
Well, I sure hope those really are just rumors.
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
やめてくださいよ
イヤなウワサだなあ
We're good to go.
（中田）
そろそろ始められます
Okay.
（渡辺･稲浪）
は～い
I'm Sono Ayano from Taharazaka Office.
（曽野(その)）
田原坂(たはらざか)オフィスの曽野あやのです
I'm auditioning for the role of Aria.
Thank you for this opportunity.
ありあ役をやります
よろしくお願いします
This is Yellow Four to Strike Leader.
イエロー４(フォー)より
ストライクリーダー
Doggie Bag has sustained heavy damage. The assault squad is all but annihilated.
ドギーバックは大破
突入部隊は壊滅状態
I ripped out every bit of my soul long ago. Do as you please.
心なんて もう捨てちゃったから
好きにして
What's your excuse for the engine's lack of durability?
（しずか）
“エンジンの耐久性は
どう言い訳をするのだ？”
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing Audition Script
Noa Ashkenazy
Page 1
Characters: Noa Ashkenazy
Scene ①
In the fighter's cockpit. Smalltalk.
Noa
"What's your excuse for the engine's lack of durability?"
Tatiana
"Uh, that's—"
Noa
"I think that the strongest recipro's the Avia S199."
Tatiana
"Huh? But that's just an inferior copy of the Bf 109! It's total trash!"
Noa
"Hmph! Skill and determination can overcome any performance issues!"
Tatiana
"You say that just after mocking the engine's durability? You aren't convincing me!"
Christine
"Heh, you two get along so well!"
Noa
"How dare you compare me to her?"
Christine
"You even breathe the same rhythm."
Noa
"You're wrong!"
Scene ②
When Noa sees the Midway Pillar
Noa
"So this is... the Midway Pillar?"
Hmph! Skill and determination can overcome any performance issues!
“フッ エンジン性能など
腕前と気力で どうにでもなる”
（声優Ａ）
あえりがとね ありあ
私を助けてくれて
Thank you, Aria! You saved me!
You aren't convincing me!
（声優Ｂ）
タチアナ的には
全然納得できないのです！
Heh, you two get along so well!
（声優Ｃ）
ウフフッ ホントにターニャも
ノアちゃんも仲よしなんだから
Heh, you two get along so well!
（声優Ｄ）
ううっ ホントにターニャも
ノアちゃんも仲よしなんだから
（声優Ｅ）
えっ ホントにターニャも
ノアちゃんも仲よしなんだから
Heh, you two get along so well!
I'm Sakaki Shizuka from Akaoni Production.
赤鬼(あかおに)プロダクションの
坂木(さかき)しずかです
I will be performing Noa's lines.
ノア役をやらせていただきます
What's your excuse for the engine's lack of durability?
エンジンの耐久性は
どう言い訳をするのだ？
Hmph! Skill and determination can overcome any performance issues!
フッ エンジン性能など
腕前と気力で どうにでもなる
How dare you compare me to her?
こんなのと
一緒にしないでください！
You're wrong!
だから違う！
So this is... the Midway Pillar?
ミッドウェイピラー これが？
Thank you. Now, please stand by.
（稲浪）
はい お疲れさまでした
お待ちください
Could we hear you do Catherine's part?
え～っと キャサリン役も
やってもらえますか？
You have a script, right?
（稲浪）
原稿 持ってます？
Yes, I do!
あ… はい 持ってます！
Thank you, Aria! You saved me!
ありがとね ありあ
私を助けてくれて
あなたが私のために流してくれた
見えない涙と血は
You shed blood and tears for me, even if you did hide them.
I'll never forget that!
絶対に忘れないよ！
I don't wanna do this. Can I just ditch?
（木下）
イヤだな～ 帰りたいよ
That'd be so rude to Atsumi-san.
（あおい）
渥美(あつみ)さんに失礼ですよ
He's gonna turn us down anyway.
いや 絶対断られるから
俺には分かるから
I can feel it.
How can you be so sure?
“絶対”って
なんで分かるんですか？
Well, one time...
（木下）昔さあ
（あおい）はい
When?
When my wife's lover left to visit his parents...
（木下）元嫁の人が実家に帰ってね
（あおい）ああ
She visited for the first time in ages,
saying we had to talk.
久しぶりに戻ってきて話があるって
俺 てっきり
仲直りできるんだと思ってたの
I thought we'd be able to start things anew, you know,
but all she wanted was a divorce.
そしたら離婚してくれ
だったんだよ
Wow...
あら…
So whenever someone wants to discuss something a second time, it's always bad news.
だからさ“改めて話”って
絶対悪い話なんだよ
Hey, none of that. Let's be a bit more optimistic.
もうちょっと
楽観的になりましょうよ
I can't! I'm the type that gets hung up on stuff.
なれるわけないよ～
俺は暗雲垂れこめる思いだぜ～
Sorry for making you wait.
（渥美）
お待たせして すみません
Not at all!
Please, you didn't at all! It's good to see you.
全然待ってないです！
お疲れさまです　何か…
Would you—
You're going to refuse, aren't you?
（木下）
やっぱりお断りですか？
ですよね？
あっ… その話なんですが
About that...
Miyamori-san, you asked me
something last time we met, before we parted.
この前 宮森(みやもり)さんから
最後に質問を頂きました
What'd she ask again?
なんでしたっけ？
She asked what I liked about clouds.
（渥美）
“雲の魅力とは何か”と
Right...
Actually, I've yet to paint one I'm satisfied with,
その答えは 描いても描いても
though I've painted more of them than I can count.
まだ満足のいく雲が
描けていないことだと思ったんです
That's because your standards are so high.
（木下）
それは理想が高いから？
Of course.
（渥美）
もちろんです
頭の中にはいつも完璧な雲がある
I'm always picturing the perfect cloud in my mind.
But I've yet to transfer that perfect image to canvas.
ですが それが100％完璧に
自分の手で
再現できたことはないんです
This places a lot of stress on me. Do you understand?
ものすごいストレスです
分かりますか？
Yeah...
（木下･あおい）はあ…
（渥美）しかし
But when my artwork goes on film and it
achieves its desired effect, it feels amazing.
いざフィルムになって
狙った効果が出ていた時は
最高の気分になるんです
I think I kind of get what you're saying.
分からないけど 分かります
If my skills and imagination can be of any use to you, I'd be grateful
俺の技術やイメージが
少しでも役に立つというなら
ありがたいです
if you utilized them.
ぜひ使ってください
（木下）えっ
（あおい）ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
U-Um, so you're taking the job?
ああっ… えっと
受けてもらえるってことですか？
That's right!
ですよ！
Though I may not live up to your standards.
どこまでやれるか
分かりませんが
No, I'm sure you will!
I'm looking forward to working with you!
（木下）
いやいや こちらこそ
よろしくお願いします！
Damn, this chair's a cheap piece of crap.
（平岡(ひらおか)）
このイス 安いやつだな
U-Um...
えっ あの…
Hey, Hiraoka-kun!
（渡辺）
ああ 平岡君
Yes?
Miyamori, let me introduce you.
ああ宮森 先に紹介しとく
新しい制作の平岡大輔(だいすけ)君
He's the new PA, Hiraoka Daisuke-kun.
She's the PM, Miyamori Aoi.
こっちがデスクの宮森あおい
The PM?
デスク？
This will be my first project as PM.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
これがデスク１本目になります
宮森です
よろしくお願いします
Your first...
１本目… ああそう
Isn't that nice?
He's Hiraoka Daisuke-san. He will be joining the production team as of today.
（興津(おきつ)）
本日から制作に加わる
平岡大輔さんです
Please introduce yourself in a few words.
簡単に自己紹介をお願いします
（平岡）
はあ… ええ 平岡です
業界歴は５年
I'm Hiraoka.
Hiraoka Daisuke
Production Assistant
I've been in the biz five years.
I started at Studio A- and have since worked at Ruin Film, Kimon Pro, and Xepeck.
所属は順番にスタジオアミン
ルーインフィルム
鬼門プロ チャペックです
My strength is that I'm well-connected. My shortcoming is my pushiness.
長所は顔の広さ
短所は強引なところ
That's all.
以上です
Welcome, Hiraoka-kun.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
よろしくね 平岡君
（太郎(たろう)）
ふんふん…
まあまあじゃないっすか
Not bad.
What are you on about?
（渡辺）
何がだよ
Merciless Audition Meeting!
We've tallied up the votes, and these are the results.
（葛城）
え～ まあ集計の結果 ざっと
こんな感じになったわけですが
Remember that the numbers are just for reference. I'd still like to hear your opinions.
Fourseasons Aria
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
Ide
Kirara
Jindaiji
Miyabi
Toyomori
Popomi
まあ この数字を参考にしつつも
捕らわれすぎずに
きたんのない意見をおっしゃって
いただければと思います
We should start with the main character, Aria.
え～っと やっぱりまずは主人公の
ありあから始めましょうか
Yeah, she is the protagonist.
ですね　主人公だし
Let's see...
（葛城）
え～っと
Suzuki Kyouko got the most votes,
Height: 150cm
From: Fukuoka
Dialect: Hakata
Range: Alto
References: JVAA Voice Actor School
Major Works
Anime
Radio
"Midnight Japan"
Drama CD
"Buyuden Fanbook 10"
票の一番多いのは
鈴木(すずき)京子(きょうこ)さんですが
but according to her profile,
she's only had a few minor roles.
プロフィールを見ると 過去に
ちょっとした役が少々くらいの
Basically, she's still a newbie.
ハッキリ言って
まだ新人さんですね
Coming in second, Moriguchi Nagisa is an experienced VA, despite her young age.
次点の森口渚(もりぐちなぎさ)さんは
まだ若いですが期待の声優さんです
Height: 150cm
From: Fukuoka
Dialect: Hakata
Range: Alto
References: JVAA Voice Actor School
Major Works
Anime
Radio
"Midnight Japan"
Drama CD
"Buyuden Fanbook 10"
Height: 150cm
From: Fukuoka
Dialect: Hakata
Range: Alto
References: JVAA Voice Actor School
Major Works
Anime
Radio
"Midnight Japan"
Drama CD
"Buyuden Fanbook 10"
Height: 150cm
From: Fukuoka
Dialect: Hakata
Range: Alto
References: JVAA Voice Actor School
Major Works
Anime
Radio
"Midnight Japan"
Drama CD
"Buyuden Fanbook 10"
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
Sizes
Hobby                 Cafe Tours
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
Blood type           O
Sizes
Hobby                 Cafe Tours
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
Dialect
Blood type           O
Sizes
Hobby                 Cafe Tours
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
From                   Hokkaido
Dialect
Blood type           O
Sizes
Hobby                 Cafe Tours
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
From                   Hokkaido
Dialect
Blood type           O
Sizes
Hobby                 Cafe Tours
Specialty             Piano
Experience
TV Anime
Video Game
Recently My Little Sister's Been Acting Weird
(Heroine: Kanzaki Mitsuki)
Angel Drill (Harigaya Hitsugi)
Sora no Risotto
Shinsei no Unind Graon
She's gained some fame these past few years.
知名度的にも ここ数年で
かなり上がってきてますね
I voted for Suzuki Kyouko-san.
僕は鈴木京子さんに入れました
Her voice is simple and nice,
声質は普通にキレイな感じですけど
何か他の人にない―
but it has this... unique flavor to it that the others lacked,
引っかかる声っていうか
特別なオーラを感じるっていうか
like a special aura around her.
That's why I voted for her.
そんな感じで
推させていただきました
Yeah, she's new, but...
そりゃ確かに経験は浅いけど…
I voted for her too. New doesn't necessarily mean bad.
私もフレッシュさ込みで
鈴木京子がいいと思いました
（水山）
私は森口渚さん推しですが
I voted for Moriguchi Nagisa-san,
Mizuyama Yasuhiro
Advertising Agency        Producer
but I thought that
Suzuki Kyouko-san was nice as well.
鈴木京子さんも
すばらしいと思ったので
I'll leave it up to you.
あとは皆さんの判断に
お任せします
Then what do we do?
（葛城）
ああ… どうしましょうか？
We should just go by the vote count.
ここは素直に
得票多い人でいいですか？
I don't mind that.
（水山）
いいんじゃないですかね？
Enjou Eisuke
Pushy Games        Producer
（遠城）
う～ん　いや～
Are you sure about this?
どうなんすかね
票的には
鈴木京子なのかもしれないけど
Suzuki Kyouko might've gotten the most votes,
but is she a good fit for this?
作品的にありなんすかね？
What do you mean?
“作品的に”って言うと？
3rd Wing is a popular franchise.
（遠城）
「サンジョ」って
人気作じゃないですか
Honestly, I think that using a
newbie in such a role is absurd.
人気作に新人ってのは
冒険しすぎなんじゃないのって
ぶっちゃけ思うんですよ
It's downright reckless.
無謀に見えなくもない
Is it?
無謀ですかね？
無謀でしょう 常識的に考えて
It is! Use your head!
Who's gonna take responsibility if you hire a newbie and she screws up?
新人起用して失敗したら
誰が責任取るのかっていう話
For an adaption of a well-known franchise, it's standard to use well-known VAs.
人気作のアニメ化なんで
当然 それなりの知名度ある
声優さんを呼ぶってのは
まあ いわばテッパンなわけだし
ファンも望んでいるはずです
The fans must want that too.
By that criteria, the one in second place,
Moriguchi Nagisa, is simply no good either.
そう考えるとハッキリ言って
次点の森口渚さんだって
弱いと思いますよ
A no-name like Suzuki Kyouko is out of question.
まして鈴木京子さんなんて
論外ですね　ありえない！
No way!
That's why I recommend Ide Kirara,
the biggest name among these candidates!
そんなわけで この候補の中では
一番の売れっ子である―
Ide Kirara
井出(いで)きららさんを
推したいと思います わたくしは
I see, I see. She is really popular after all.
なるほど なるほど
まあ 井出きららさん
大人気だからな
Hold on a moment!
Yarase Takumi
R.I.G. Music        Producer
（屋良瀬(やらせ)）
ちょっと待って！
You want Ide Kirara? You aren't considering the songs, are you?!
井出きららさんだった場合
歌う大前提で考えると
She can't sing, can she now?
この人 結構
歌苦手じゃなかったっけ？
There was a disclaimer saying she can't sing!
Note:
No singing please
Cosplay negotiable
備考欄に“キャラソンＮＧ”って
なってるじゃない
This is a major issue!
これ大問題よ
歌込みのことまで総合的に考えると
Taking the songs into consideration,
I'd say Jindaiji Miyabi is our only option!
深大寺雅(じんだいじみやび)さんにするべきです！
Then we can do character songs all day!
キャラソンも出し放題！
We had plans for those?
（葛城）キャラソン出すんですか？
（木下）作品に合うかな？
Would that even fit the show?
合う合わないじゃなくて
やりましょうよ！
Doesn't matter if it fits or not! Just do it! Everyone does it!
どこもやってるし
歌えない声優なんて
今どきありえない！
Hiring a VA who can't sing is insane!
No, it's not. A VA's job is what it says, voice acting.
ありえますよ　声優の本業は声優
You're so old-fashioned.
ああ 古いな～ 考え方が
That's why the anime industry's falling by the wayside. Where's the showmanship?
そんなんだから
アニメ業界しぼんでいくんすよ！
昭和じゃないんだから！
We should just pick Jindaiji Miyabi, period!
ここは無難に
深大寺雅にしようよ！
個人的に仲いい事務所だから
声かけやすいんだよね～
Not to mention I know the agency well,
so it'd be an easy hire.
Jindaiji Miyabi it is!
よ～し 深大寺雅でいこう！
Just singing isn't enough nowadays.
Makurada Tsuyoshi
DK Race Creative        Producer
（枕田）
歌だけ考えてもしょうがないでしょ
We must consider everything, live performances included.
今やイベント稼働込みの
トータルで考えていかなきゃ
If we look at the situation realistically,
そういう部分も加味して
冷静に分析すると
it's clear that Toyomori Popomi should be our choice!
間違いなく
豊森(とよもり)ぽぽみでしょうね！
Just look at her figure! She's amazing!
見てください このスタイル
おおっ ヤバいでしょ
きっとイベントの映えも違う
I can almost see her shining on stage!
She's fine with wearing swimsuits and cosplay too!
プロフにコスプレも
水着もオーケーって
書いてあるじゃないですか
Add some extras to the limited edition,
and sales will be spectacular!
初回購入特典つけて
爆上げ必死です
The acting stuff is important, of course,
本業も大事なことは
百も承知ですが
but we should focus on the visual appeal for now!
Fourseasons Aria
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
Ide
Kirara
Jindaiji
Miyabi
Toyomori
Popomi
これからは見た目を
どんどん重視するべきなんです！
And she's got the boobs!
おっぱいも でかいし
いや おっぱい関係ないでしょ
That's irrelevant.
No, it's not!
少しはあるでしょ！
When you put something in the fridge,
please write your name and the date on it.
私物を冷蔵庫に入れる時は
名前と日付を書いておいてください
Do you have any other questions?
何か他に
分からないことありますか？
Will there be a second season of Exodus?
「えくそだすっ！」２期やんの？
ああ いえ そういう話は…
I don't know about that.
Of course not. Not with its lousy 4 or 5 thousand copies sold.
（平岡）
まずないよね
４～5,000の売り上げじゃ
Oh, and I heard from Tomigaya...
あと富ヶ谷(とみがや)に聞いたんだけど
Ah, from G.I. Staff?
あっ はい Ｇ.Ｉ.STAFFの…
Segawa-san's nice to girls so she works fast,
but you you'd better not get spoiled by that.
瀬川(せがわ)さん　あの人 女に優しいから
仕事早く上げてくれるけど
あんまり甘えないほうがいいよ
What's his problem? He's so unpleasant.
（ロロ）
なんだろ 態度キツいね
He's deliberately being mean to you! What an asshole!
（ミムジー）
気付きなよ 嫌みだよ
イヤなヤツ！
Do you think so?
えっ やっぱそうかな？
Beat him to pulp!
ミンチにしちゃえ！
Stop! She only just met him!
やめなよ！
会ったばっかの人に
Miyamori!
（渡辺）宮森！
（ミムジー･ロロ）あっ！
Please bring out some more tea.
お茶 おかわり頼む
S-Sure.
あっ はい
Look...
あのさあ この際だから
言わしてもらうけど
Let me put this as simply as I can!
It's pointless if the show can't grab the spotlight!
みんなに注目されなければ
意味ないんだよね 作品は
Put as many famous VAs as possible on the cast,
and make sure it's always trending on the Internet!
有名声優バンバン
ドカーンって出してね
ネットとかで ワイワイ
盛り上がってほしいわけなんですよ
We're trying to make sales, you know?
売る側の人間としては！
That means Ide Kirara is our only choice! Everyone else isn't a viable option!
そう考えると
井出きららさんしか考えられないし
異論挟む余地なんてないでしょ？
I personally like her acting a lot,
（木下）井出きららさんのお芝居…
（あおい）失礼します
Excuse me!
（木下）
個人的にはすごく好きですよ
but she has a very high-pitched voice.
ただ 声のトーンがかなり高いんで
クールなトーンのありあだと
That doesn't mesh with the cool image I have for Aria.
僕のイメージと違うんですよね
Suzuki Kyouk—
鈴木京子さんのほうが…
Who said she's the cool type?
クールなトーンなんて
誰が聞いたんですか？
Well, that was just my impression...
（木下）
あっ いや そう思った
だけなんですけど…
See! That's only something you made up yourself!
そう それは監督の
勝手な先入観なんです！
一般論じゃない
It's nonsense!
Even if you want Suzuki Kyouko-san,
Fourseasons Aria
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
Ide
Kirara
Jindaiji
Miyabi
Toyomori
Popomi
監督がいくら
鈴木京子さんを推薦しようと
no one knows who she is!
ぶっちゃけ 鈴木京子さんなんて
誰も知らないし
She's not even on Wikipedia!
ウィキペディアにも載ってない
We want a VA who will carry the show,
not one who will get carried by the show!
作品におんぶにだっこじゃなくて
ドドーンと推せる声優さんに
任せるべきですよ
Suzuki or Moriguchi won't
get us viewers! Am I wrong?
鈴木 森口じゃ客は呼べない！
違いますか？
You want the series to sell, don't you?
監督だって
ブルーレイ売りたいでしょ？
It must feel like crap when it
doesn't sell, huh? Like your last show.
イヤでしょ？　売れないの
前回みたいに！
W-Well...
あっ まあ…
Let's get realistic, director.
（遠城）大人になろうよ～ 監督
（水山）あの すいません
Allow me to interject.
The director's personal ideas aside, I don't really think Ide Kirara would fit the role either.
あの 監督の肩を
持つわけじゃないけど
あの 井出きららさん
やっぱり僕も合わないと思います
Her selling point is her extremely soprano voice.
井出きららさんの特長って
スーパーソプラノボイス
じゃないですか
You can't seriously have our quiet ace pilot sound like Mickey Mouse. It feels wrong.
無口な孤高のエースパイロットが
ミッキーボイスって
違和感を覚えます
Then let it feel wrong! Who cares?!
違和感を覚えるヤツには
覚えさせときゃいいんです！
That's decided, then!
（水山）いやいや…
（遠城）はい ではそんな感じで…
Hold your horses! Ide Kirara would mean no business for us!
待って待って！
井出きららじゃ うちの会社
商売あがったりなんだよ！
We can't sell any CDs with her!
ＣＤ売れないじゃん！
Anime and songs go hand in hand!
アニメと歌は
切っても切れないんだから
Jindaiji Miyabi has released tons of albums.
She's the clear choice!
アルバムいっぱい出してる
深大寺雅さんで決まりでしょ！
大御所だし！
She's a veteran too!
いやいや 大御所すぎですよ
Too much of a veteran, if you ask me!
How old was she again? I'm just saying.
言わせてもらうけど
深大寺雅ってさ 年齢的に…
So you're going to play the age card?
It doesn't matter!
あっ 年齢のこと言うんすか
関係ないっしょ！
（遠城）ありますよ！
（屋良瀬）ないよ！
Oh yes, it does!
No, it doesn't!
Well, I'd say that the age of the VA isn't too important as long as the voice matches the character...
Fourseasons Aria
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
いや あのですね
個人的には合ってさえいれば
声優さんと登場人物の年齢は
無関係だと思っています
but I think Jindaiji Miyabi is a bit of a stretch.
ですが 深大寺雅さんに関しては…
That's right!
そうなんですよ！
だってもうすぐ還暦じゃん
She's almost 60! You can't possibly have her do a 17-year-old's voice!
還暦で17歳役ってどうよ？
Why not? Just hire her and that's it!
ありでしょ！
ありにしちゃえばいいんだよ！
It'd be a refreshing change!
（屋良瀬）逆に新鮮でしょ！
（枕田）新鮮じゃないですよ
No, it wouldn't. No one would go to her live shows.
イベント 客呼べないですよ
どうすんですか？
Let's go with Toyomori Popomi!
豊森ぽぽみさんでいきましょう！
But Toyomori Popomi's lack of experience...
Fourseasons Aria
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
いや あの
豊森ぽぽみさんって履歴には…
う～ん 何も書いてないですね
あっ 新人さん？
It doesn't list any experience.
Is she new?
She's got no voice acting experience, so in a way, yes.
声の仕事の経験がないので
新人と言えば新人ですね
She's a gravure idol.
本職はグラビアアイドルです
Gravure idols are the best!
う～ん
グラビアアイドル最高！
But her performance at the audition was quite...
オーディションテープ聞くと
かなりその… 演技が…
Lackluster.
棒ですよね
That's the point! She sounds innocent!
だがそこがいい！
純粋な感じがよく出ている！
Fresh blood in lead roles is all the rage!
今 素人が
主役張るのってざらですよ！
And those boobs!
（枕田）おっぱい でかいし
（葛城）だから関係ないでしょ
Which are still irrelevant.
I'm looking forward to recording and taking her out for drinks afterwards.
楽しみだな～ アフレコとその後の
豊森ぽぽみとの飲み会
Let it be Jindaiji Miyabi, please!
深大寺雅さんにしてくださいよ
I've already made arrangements. I can't back out now!
うちうちで声かけちゃった
自分の立場はどうなるんすか～
It should be Ide Kirara.
井出きららでしょ
Who cares if she doesn't fit?
The audience will get used to it.
違和感あるっていっても
３本くらいとりゃあ みんな慣れる
That's how anime works! All's well if it sells!
アニメなんてそんなもん
売れれば正義だし
売れなきゃただの負け犬！
No sales, you lose!
I don't care! My company and I want Jindaiji Miyabi!
（屋良瀬）
負け犬でもいい！
我が社としては断じて
深大寺雅です！
Toyomori Popomi-chan's the only choice!
豊森ぽぽみちゃんでしょ！
Ud— I mean, Ide Kirara!
うで… いやいや 井出きららで！
How'd it go?
（太郎）どうだった どうだった？
（あおい）知りませんよ
Don't ask me.
So who is it? Who's it gonna be?
ウソだ～ 誰 誰
誰に決まりそう？
I wasn't listening.
（あおい）聞いてないですもん
（太郎）え～ 聞いとけよ～
Why weren't you?!
はあ～ う～ん
どうしますかね 葛城さん
What do we do, Katsuragi-san?
Inanami-san, what do you say, as the sound director?
稲浪さん 音響監督の立場として
どう思われますか？
She's got four votes out of nine despite being pretty new.
まっ 新人でありながら
９票中 ４票っていうのは
That means there has to be something to Suzuki Kyouko-san, at least.
鈴木京子さん 何か持ってるって
ことなんでしょうね
I've seen her in a bunch of minor roles,
and she was pretty good.
端役 何度かやってもらってますが
上手でしたよ　彼女
On the other hand, those with one vote each won't betray our expectations. That much is for sure.
逆に１票ずつの方たちは
化けたりハマったりする可能性も
ないとはいえ…
Right?
（屋良瀬）でしょ？
（枕田）そうなんですよ
You're right!
We can't find out unless we try!
やってみなければ
分かんないからね！
（稲浪）
ですが お三方
But you're rating them by their popularity,
singing ability, and figure. Everything but their acting.
人気 歌唱 容姿と
演技以外で選んでる
That is an issue.
（稲浪）そこが問題です
（屋良瀬）いいじゃん別に
Who cares?
Everyone does that!
みんなやってることでしょ？
This reeks of vested interests.
政治的なキャスティング臭がします
You can't know that!
（枕田）分かんないですよ！
（遠城）割り切りは大事！
Someone's gotta decide!
It's obvious if you're picking a cast this way.
政治的なキャスティングは
必ずバレます
I can say for sure that it doesn't add anything to a project. Never does.
そして それは断言できますが
作品にプラスになることはない
絶対にです
I understand your concerns about Suzuki Kyouko-san's experience, or lack thereof.
一方で鈴木京子さんの
経験の少なさが
不安という意見も理解できます
That means...
その時は
We'll give her that experience.
私たちが育てればいいんですよ
（ドアが開く音）
（茶沢(ちゃざわ)）遅れちゃってすんませ～ん
Sorry I'm late!
Funny thing is, Musashi-Sakai's so far!
いや変な話
遠いっすね 武蔵境(むさしさかい)
Suzuki
Kyouko
Moriguchi
Nagisa
Ide
Kirara
Jindaiji
Miyabi
Toyomori
Popomi
ああ 茶沢さんお疲れさまです
Chazawa-san, thank you for coming.
We were debating giving Aria's role to Suzuki Kyou—
今 ありあを鈴木京子さんに
するかどうか決め…
（茶沢）
ああ～ いいんじゃないっすか
まあ先生も特になさそうだし
That sounds nice!
The author's got no problems with her either, so just go for it!
いいでしょ いいでしょ
はいはい
Moriguchi
Nagisa
Ide
Kirara
Jindaiji
Miyabi
アハハ… では原作者サイドの
承認も得たことだし
That means we've got the author's approval for it too.
Suzuki Kyouko-san gets the role of Aria.
ありあは鈴木京子さんに
決定いたしました
Next up, let's decide on Tatiana.
（まばらな拍手）
では次に タチアナいきましょう
Excuse me!
（あおい）
失礼します
I'm telling you, if we go by popularity,
picking anyone but Hitohira-san would be foolish!
（遠城）
いやだから 人気といえば
仁平(ひとひら)さんしかありえない！
A fool has no place calling others fools!
（枕田）
ありえないってのが
そもそもありえない！
Just check out Hanajiri-san's butt!
それより花尻(はなじり)さんのお尻
見てくださいよ
Her butt doesn't do the talking!
尻がしゃべるわけじゃない！
How do you know that?!
分かんないですよ？
I just got a great idea!
いいこと思いついた！
もう面倒だし
Arguing like this sucks, so let's just pick on based on how many Twitter followers they have!
ツイッターのフォロアー数の
多い順に適当に選んじゃいましょう
Or the number of hits their name gets on Google!
ググって検索数
多い順でもいいですが
あっ 今回オーディション
参加してないけどね
How about Kunitachi Netsuko-san?
I know she didn't audition, but still!
国立(くにたち)ネス子さん どうですか？
She's in the third reserve team.
第３キープまで入ってます
Then we can just scrap everyone else, right?
おっしゃ～
全部抜きにしちゃえばありですかね
We can't boot all our regulars!
いやいや レギュラーで全部抜きは
ありえないですよ
We can do whatever we want, dammit!
Toyomori
Popomi
Jindaiji
Miyabi
Ide
Kirara
やっかしいよ！
そうかなって もう～
I know she lacks VA experience, but we could put in a singer who's under contract with my company.
声優経験ないけど
我が社と専属契約してる歌手
１人入れましょうよ
（葛城）すいません
（屋良瀬）アハハ…
I'd rather we didn't.
Sure, her acting might be bad, but the five other pros will make up for it, right?
下手だったとしても
レギュラー５人に混ざれば―
どうせ分かりゃしないっすよ～！
（枕田）それより尻が！
It's all about the ass!
Please, can't we get to the bottom of this?
Tatiana
Hanajiri
Ran
Jinpira
Koyori
Nagai
Tsukasa
Tokiwa
Hiroko
LaFresia
Miho
すみません
あの話聞いてください！
そろそろ決を採りたいんですが
You mean Hanajiri's bottom?!
（枕田）花尻さんのケツですか？
（葛城）違います！
No!
Excuse me.
（あおい）
失礼します
Haotome-san's neck! Her neck is great!
（枕田）
羽乙女(はおとめ)さんの
くびれ～が くびく～び♪
（遠城）お前はもう黙ってろ！
（枕田）“お前”とはなんすか
Just shut up already!
How dare you say that?
I'm just judging them objectively by their looks!
人がせっかく外見だけ見て
一生懸命 選んでんのに！
Who cares? Just pick someone from my exclusive agency!
いいかげん うちと懇意の
事務所からも選んでくださいよ！
I can't leave empty handed. My boss would kill me!
手ぶらじゃ帰れないし
上司にも僕 怒られちゃう！
Anyone popular will do, even a guy!
They can just use falsetto or something!
この際 人気さえある声優なら
男でもいいでしょ
ちょっと裏声でやってもらえば
Then what'd we do at live events?
Make 'em cross-dress?
（枕田）
イベントとかどうすんですか
女装でもさせるんですか？
It's like ghostwriters!
We'll have ghostevents! No problem!
（遠城）
ゴーストライターならぬ
ゴーストイベントで
いいんじゃないんですかね
It's anything but fine!
よかねえよ！
なんで俺の意見もだ…
Why isn't anyone... Why isn't anyone listening to me?
誰も聞いてくれねえんだよ！
We're investing in this! We're clients!
うちは出資してるんだぞ！
クライアントなんだぞ！
（遠城）うちもだよ！
（屋良瀬）うちもっすよ！
We are too!
So are we!
Sorry! Funny thing is, I just got another appointment,
（茶沢）
すいません　変な話
別件入っちゃったんで
あとはお任せしますよ
so I'll leave the rest to you. Toodles!
お疲れっした～！
Please! We've already decided that Tatiana will be played by Tokiha-san!
皆さん タチアナは
常磐(ときは)さんに決まったんです
蒸し返さないでください！
Please, just drop it already!
They're quite fired up, huh?
（丸川）
なかなか白熱してるじゃない
They've been at it for fourteen hours already.
（あおい）
もうかれこれ
14時間もやってます
Don't worry about them.
（丸川）
結構 結構
じゃあ これ夜食ね
Take this to the room, please. Midnight snacks.
お願い
I brought some midnight snacks.
（あおい）
お夜食 お持ちしました
Ah, the president's homemade dumplings.
（木下）
ああ～ 社長の手作りギョーザ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Yarase-san's not coming back.
（葛城）
屋良瀬さん 戻って来ませんね
He must be reporting to his boss.
上司に報告してるんじゃ
ないんすか
Probably getting an earful for failing to get things his way!
ゴリ押し失敗して
きっと怒られてるんですよ
Anyway, let's get this done!
いいから とっとと決めましょ！
Can't we just rig the votes next time?
次から出来レース枠
作りましょうよ
Not as long as we are involved.
Catherine
Weller
Itou
Suzuka
Musasabi
Taeko
Saotome
Kaede
Terazaki
Mei
Tachibana
Soyori
うちと組む以上 それはありません
Think about all the poor people who showed up for auditions!
出来レースなんてやったら
頑張ってオーディションに望んだ
声優さんたちがかわいそうです
Fixing a role beforehand is negotiable...
決め打ちの相談なら
まだ分かるけど
Fine, fine, whatever. You're all such sticklers.
はいはい… 分かりましたよ
みんな真面目だな～
I don't care anymore!
Can we just decide already? I'm beat.
どうでもいいんで 決めましょう
疲れちゃった
Catherine's the last character we need to discuss.
で… 最後のキャラ
キャサリンですが
What do you say? I'd like someone with skills we can rely on.
どうですかね？
私はこのキャラは
手堅くうまい声優さんで
押さえたいと思いましたが
She's bright and mysterious at the same time. Fitting her character won't be easy.
明るくてミステリアスな
少女ですからね
かなりテクニカルな役作りが
要求されると思います
So someone flexible enough.
器用なほうがいいでしょう
People that fit that criteria would be...
Itou Suzuka-san and Musasabi Taeko-san.
え～ ということは
この中では
Tachibana
Soyori
Terazaki
Mei
Saotome
Kaede
Musasabi
Taeko
Itou
Suzuka
Catherine
Weller
伊藤(いとう)鈴鹿(すずか)さん むささび妙子(たえこ)さん
あたりですかね？
（木下）
あ～ あっ あの…
Um...
Yes?
（葛城）
はい
This Sakaki Shizuka girl caught my eye.
この“坂木しずか”って
人なんですけど
From Yamagata Prefecture
Height
Experience:
Variety show Mysterious Happenings Around the World  voice-over
Akaoni Production
（葛城）
坂木しずか？
Sakaki Shizuka?
Who's that?
（遠城）誰それ？
（枕田）知らないっす
No idea.
（水山）
ああ ノア役で
オーディション来てて
Ah, she's the one who came for Noa's role, but we had her do Catherine too, right?
急きょキャサリン
やってもらった人ですね
Yeah. She's probably a newbie, but what did you think?
ええ あっ多分
新人さんなんですけど
どうですかね
She's my second pick.
僕の第２候補なんですけど
She didn't come prepared to read Catherine's lines,
坂木さん 即興で
キャサリン演じたのに
but she seemed to understand the character.
しっかりキャラを抑えていたなって
Her voice fit too, in my opinion.
声のトーンとしても
ありかと思ったんですが
I am assigned to the Chofu Base 3rd Fighter Wing as of today!
（しずか）
本日付で 調布基地 第307飛行体に
着任いたしました
I am Ensign Catherine Weller!
キャサリン･ウェラー
少尉であります
ほお～ キレイな声ですね
Please, just call me Cathy.
She's got a nice voice.
No, I can't recall anything yet.
She's good, and sounds so confident. Is she really new?
うまいし自信持ってやってますね
新人とは思えない
I remember how to pilot, for some reason, but nothing else.
But compared to the power of Itou Suzuka-san or Musasabi Taeko-san,
けど…
伊藤鈴鹿さん むささび妙子さんの
パワーに比べると
Don't you think it'd be weird if I didn't have a name?
she's still got a ways to go.
やっぱり
あと一歩な感じもしますよね
So I just picked a name for myself.
I mean, she's good, but still.
いや いいんですけどね
ああ… そっか
I see...
It's fine.
Musasabi Taeko
Voice Animal
Sakaki Shizuka
Akaoni Production
Might be
good?
ああ いえいえ
いいです いいです
I was just throwing out ideas.
ちょっといいかなって
思っただけなんで
Well then, who should it be?
え～ ではどうしましょうか
I looked at the schedules.
Itou-san could come on Thursday.
スケジュールは伊藤さんが
木曜オーケー
Musasabi Taeko-san's waiting on results from two other auditions, and she's in a backup team too.
むささび妙子さんは
２件オーディション結果待ちと
キープありです
She's waiting to hear back from them? Too bad.
“結果待ち”って惜しいな～
Why can't they just tell her
whether she got the role or not?
決まるにしても決まらないにしても
早くバラしてあげたいですよね
こういうの
It's so annoying how this industry likes to keep people hanging "just in case."
なんでもかんでも
とりあえずキープってのは
ホント 業界の悪癖ですよ
But enough of that. This fall's schedule seems to favor Itou Suzuka-san.
まあ愚痴はともかく
この空きの状況だと
伊藤鈴鹿さんですかね
I think she fits the role too.
イメージ合うと思います
She's a safe call too. Sounds good to me.
安心の伊藤鈴鹿
いいんじゃないですか
Fine by me. Whatever.
（遠城）いいっすよ 別に
（枕田）私も
Same.
では 伊藤鈴鹿さんで決まりです
Itou Suzuka-san it is.
That sums up the regulars' auditions.
レギュラーオーディション会議は
以上になります　お疲れさまでした
Thank you.
（一同）
お疲れさまでした
Should I call a taxi for you?
（渡辺）
タクシー呼びますか？
Lemme go over it one last time.
（みどり）
えっと 確認ですけど
You need the consumption and price of the Kfir C2
クフィルＣ２(ツー)の
燃料と価格ですよね？
and its max cruise distance?
あと最長航行距離
Yeah, that'll do for now. Thanks a lot!
うん　今回はとりあえずそれを
よろしくお願いします
Sorry. So the question is how a solo Kfir could get from Tel Aviv to Chofu, right?
あっ すいません
単独でテルアビブを離陸した
クフィルが
調布(ちょうふ)に到着するには
どうすればいいかですよね？
Yeah. In the original story,
it doesn't explain how Noa gets there,
そう　原作だとノアが
いきなりいるんだけどさ
but would that be possible in real life?
これってリアルに考えると
どうなんだろうって
Not to mention the Tree's 20 kilometers tall.
Can it even fly that high?
…っていうかツリーの高さって
２万メートルだよね
その高度で飛べるんだっけ？
Background
In the 1960s, the French Mirage III constituted the backbone of the Israeli Air Force. However, after the Six-Day War of 1967, French arms exports to Israel were terminated due to a change of Charles De Gaulle's cabinet's stance towards the Middle-Eastern situation. The 50 already finished Mirage 5s (a version of the Mirage III with simplified electronics to improve its operation rate in action) were subject to that embargo too. This triggered the development of the Kfir.
They already had a license for the Mirage 5 airframe from Dassault. They added the Atar 9C engine to it, details of which they acquired through espionage.
This combination named Nesher (meaning vulture in Hebrew) could be called a self-produced Mirage. However, the IAF wre unsatisfied with the performance
of the engine in high altitudes and high temperatures.
They decided to use the J79 engine of the American F-4E, already in IAF service. They also modified the airframe to improve performance, and applying
these changes to the Nesher resulted in the Kfir.
The Mirage III fitted with the J79 made its first flight in September 1970. The improved prototype of that, the Ra'am (Hebrew for thunder) took off first in June 1973. There were unconfirmed reports that a number of the original Mirage IIICs, re-engined with the J79 and given the name Barak (Hebrew for lightning), took part in the Yom Kippur War of 1973. The version optimized for the J79 entered service as the Kfir in April 1975, after the end of the conflict.
Since the J79 turbojet engine is a U.S design, although made in Israel, all export sales of the Kfir are subject to prior approval from the U.S. State
Department, a fact that has limited the sale of the Kfir to foreign nations.
Before the introduction of the F-16N, the US Marine Corps leased a number of Kfirs and used them under the name of F-21 as aggressors. It was valued
for its ability to simulate the MiG-21 well.
It is already retired from IAF service, but a good number of them are still preserved, some sold to other countries after modernization refitting. The IAI relaunched Kfir production and CEO Joseph Weiss stated on 2014. April 3. that Argentina might be one of the new customers.
Features
Its appearance is much alike the Mirage 5, on which it was based. However, the J79's thrust is more than 2t over the Atar 9C, allowing for better
maneuverability and an extra 1.5t payload.
Using the J79 also required a major redesign of the airframe. The rear fuselage was slightly shortened and widened, its air intakes were enlarged,
and a large air inlet was installed at the base of the vertical stabilizer, so as to supply the extra cooling needed for the afterburner. The tail was
shortened by 0.6m for balancing reasons.
It can, but the fuel consumption would be affected.
（舞茸(まいたけ)）
飛べますが燃費が変わってくるかな
I don't think we need to worry about that.
（木下）
そこは あんまりこだわらなくても
There is a difference between not knowing, and knowingly ignoring.
でも 分からないまま描くのと
分かった上で忘れるのは
違いますからね
Oh right, Miyamori-san. Could you look up everything we've talked about today?
そんでさ 宮森さん
今 話に出たことを追加で
調べてもらってくれないかな
Ask Dr. Diesel.
ディーゼルさんに
She could even just sit in with us.
…っていうかディーゼルさん
もうここに直接降臨してほしいよ
We might need someone to oversee settings production this time.
（丸川）
今回は設定制作が
必要かもしれないね
Thank you.
すいません
The series has a lot of different settings.
設定の量が量だし
But she's still a student, isn't she?
Does she have the time?
でもその子 まだ学生なんだろ
時間あんの？
I guess she could come after classes, in the evening.
夕方授業が終わってからなら
来てくれるんじゃないかと
In that case...
（丸川）
じゃあさ 一度会社に
連れてきてくれる？
Why don't you call her here?
（丸川）話してみるね
（あおい）はい
I'll talk with her.
Okay.
We'd like to ask you to handle settings production.
（丸川）
今回頼みたい仕事は設定制作ね
はい
I see.
You'll look up facts we need in order to write the scenario,
シナリオを書くために
必要な資料を集めたり
check to make sure phrases are always used correctly, and make lists of items that appear in the show.
表現が間違っていないか調べたり
出てくるアイテムを一覧表にしたり
Okay.
はい
I heard you aspire to be a scriptwriter. Are you fine with working here?
（丸川）
脚本志望って聞いたけど
うちで働くのは大丈夫？
Of course.
はい！
Do you have any questions?
何か聞きたいことある？
Um... In Boomin, Marukawa-san was credited with settings production. Was that you?
あの 「ブミーン」で設定で
クレジットされていた丸川さんって
社長さんのことなんでしょうか？
Yeah, that was me!
アハハ… そう僕
もう40年近く前だね
That was forty or so years ago though.
And Shirobeko too?
（みどり）「白べこ」もですか？
（丸川）よく調べてるね！
You looked that up too?
I love it! Learning about things, I mean.
好きなんです！
あっ 知らなかったことを
知るのが好きなんです
I also found out that you worked in
theater before coming to this industry.
丸川社長が業界に入る前は
演劇に携わっていたことも
知りました
We'd like you to join as soon as possible.
来れるんなら
すぐにでも来てもらいたいんだけど
That's fine!
大丈夫です！
Then can you start tomorrow?
じゃあ あしたからは？
Right away if you wanna! I mean, if you'd like me to.
今からでもオーケーっす！
あっ… です
Director! This is Imai-san.
She's going to do settings production.
（あおい）
監督 設定制作に入ってもらう
今井(いまい)さんです
Ah. Hello.
ああ どうも
I'm Imai Midori. Nice to meet you.
今井みどりです
よろしくお願いします
え～っと…
Ah, Dr. Diesel herself?
（円(まどか)）お～ 生ディーゼルさんか
（木下）あっ おい！
Hey!
After all the research you did for us on diesel trains for Exodus,
（山田(やまだ)）
「えくそだすっ！」で
ディーゼル車のこと
調べてくれたんで
we started referring to you as Dr. Diesel.
もう 俺たちの間じゃ
ディーゼルさん
Sorry for the kind-of-rude nickname.
（木下）
いや ごめん！　失礼な呼び方で
Not at all. Diesel suits me just fine!
いえ ぜひディーゼルと
呼んでください！
Matsu
Tei
Food and Drinks
Here's to Mii-chan and Rii-chan moving closer and closer to their dreams!
（あおい）
今日はみーちゃん りーちゃんズの
一歩前進祝いってことで
Rii-chan's gonna work part-time at Musani.
（美沙(みさ)）
りーちゃんはムサニで
バイトすることが決まって
Mii-chan-senpai's moved to another company!
みーちゃん先輩は別の会社に
移ることになったんです
Really? Then just drink up today!
ホント？
じゃあ今日は飲んで飲んで！
But you're gonna have it tough from now on,
Mii-chan, with all the planes.
（絵麻(えま)）
でも これからみーちゃんは
飛行機ばっかりで
大変そうだよね
Rii-chan's job is all about planes too.
りーちゃんもだよ
飛行機漬け
I had an audition for a show about planes just the other day too.
私もこないだ飛行機関係の
オーディション受けてきたよ
I didn't get the part though.
落ちちゃったけどね
Really? What was it?
（あおい）へえ～
（絵麻）どんな仕事？
It was the 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
（しずか）
「第三飛行少女隊」っていう
That's... the show we're all doing.
それ 今度うちでやる
Huh?
えっ あっ そうなんだ
Oh... I see.
It would've been great to work with you all.
みんなと一緒に仕事したかったけど
Next time, I guess!
でもまあ しかたないよね
それより聞いて！
But guess what!
They asked me to try a second role while I was there. Now that's a first!
初めてオーディションの現場で
“別の役もやってみて”って
言われたよ
I still didn't get the part,
but I think I'm getting somewhere!
落ちちゃったんだけど
これも一歩前進だよね
My teacher told me that I should go in confident and determined.
先生に言われたの
“自信を持て 覚悟をしろ”って
So that's what I did!
だから私 そうすることにした！
Zuka-chan-senpai, you're so awesome!
（みどり）
ずかちゃん先輩 かっけえっす！
うん… 頑張るよ！
I try.
Hmm...
（木下）
う～ん　オーケー
Okay!
Are they fine?
（井口(いぐち)）
大丈夫ですか？
Yeah. I'd love to see them in action right away.
うん すぐにでも動かしたい
I'll get episode 1's storyboards done soon!
俺 １話の絵コンテ
絶対早く上げる！
イヒヒ… あっ みゃーもりん
Oh right, Miyamori.
You get any responses about my
sketches of the main characters?
こないだのメインキャラのラフ
返事どうなってるっけ？
I asked Watanabe-san about them.
（あおい）
渡辺さんに
聞いてもらってるんですけど
Funny thing is, the author's feeling kinda depressed.
（茶沢）
いや～ 変な話 先生今
精神的にダウナーなお時期で
It's not about the anime, is it?
まさか アニメのことで？
Nah, it's nothing like that.
（茶沢）
いや関係ないと思いますけど
そんなわけで当面はお任せで
Point is, I'll leave it all to you.
So we're good to go?
つまり 進めても
かまわないってことですか？
Yeah, yeah! Just go ahead.
（茶沢）
あ～ そんな感じで はいはい
I made a rough production schedule.
制作のローテーションを
組んでみたんですけど
We can only handle eleven episodes with in-house manpower.
社内戦力で作るのは
11本が限界です
We'll have to outsource two episodes to a third party.
２本はどうしても制作グロスで
受けてくれる会社に発注しないと
What about Verde Company?
う～ん　ヴェルデカンパニーは？
They're already heading another project.
Do you know anyone else who would do it?
もう元請けの仕事が決まったって
どこか他に心当たりありませんか？
I can't come up with anything off the top of my head.
う～ん 今すぐにな～
思いつかないな
I know companies that'd take the job, if I asked them.
（平岡）
受けてくれるところありますよ
俺が声かければ
Want me to introduce you?
紹介しましょうか？
Studio Taitanic? I've heard about them,
but I've never worked with them myself.
（本田(ほんだ)）
スタジオ･タイタニックね～
Matcha Cake
Chocolate Cake
Strawberry Cake
聞いたことあるんだけど
頼んだことないな
I see...
（あおい）
そうですか
But I'd just look at it as broadening your network.
（本田）
でもまあ つきあいが
広がるのは いいことだと思うよ
I know. I'm reminded just how much skill and experience I lack every day.
はい　自分のキャパとか
経験値とか
いろいろ足りなさを
思い知らされる日々です
Everyone starts like that.
（本田）
誰だって最初はそうだよ
チャレンジ チャレンジ
Keep challenging yourself!
There you go. That'll be 1,236 yen.
はい お会計
１,２３６円になります
Please bill it to Musashino Animation.
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションで
領収書お願いします
As you wish.
かしこまりました
Excuse me!
（あおい）
失礼します
Good morning!
おはようございます
Good morning?
おはようございま～す
うわっ！
Musani, Musani... Let's see.
（デスク）
ムサニ ムサニ
ムサニさんっと
I'd like to ask your help with 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
（あおい）
あっ　はい
「第三飛行少女隊」
のことで
Yeah, I've heard from Hiraoka-chan.
平岡ちゃんから話は聞いてる
Then let's jump right into it.
（あおい）
そしたら早速お話しさせて
いただきたいんですけど
This is the schedule.
こちらがスケジュールになります
Um...
あのさあ
Is Director Kinoshita picky about the details?
木下監督ってこだわるタイプ？
Huh?
This is Musani.
（平岡）
はいムサニです　ああ富ヶ谷
久しぶり 平岡だよ
Ah, Tomigaya? Long time. It's Hiraoka.
Yeah, I'm doing fine.
ああ なんとか生き延びてるよ
Next time on Shirobako: "Will Drawings Like This Do?"
次回「SHIROBAKO(シロバコ)」
Will Drawings Like This Do?